<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>AWS on iamqh's Blog</title><link>/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in AWS on iamqh's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>vi-vn</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>EC2 Purchasing Options</title><link>/everyday/ec2-purchasing-options/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/everyday/ec2-purchasing-options/</guid><description>EC2 Purchasing Options On-Demand Reversed Spot Dedicated Hosts Metrics On-Demand Reserved Spot Discount 0% 40%-60% 50%-90% Description There’s no commitment from you. You pay the most with this option. 1-year or 3-year commitment from you. You save money from that commitment Ridiculously inexpensive because there’s no commitment from the AWS side. Use Case Small or experimental project that do not anticipate the need of config to be used or used in a short time such as: Software testingBuild a system that runs seasonallyThe system needs to be deployed quickly but can stop at any time (actively) A server for long-term purpose Limited costApplications can stop at any time without affecting the system: Like jobs that need to be processed once requiring high processing speed, CI/CD, &amp;hellip; EC2 Spot EC2 Spot vs On-Demand Metrics Spot Instances On-Demand Instances Launch time Launches instantly if the Spot Request is active and capacity is available.</description></item><item><title>AWS Storage Performance</title><link>/everyday/aws-compute-performance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/everyday/aws-compute-performance/</guid><description>Things need to consider:
Sharing
Will the data have to be shared between different instances
Latency
How quickly this data that needs to be accessible
Throughput
How fast data can move from side of our process to the next
Persistence
Must know the data is persistence or if it could be volatile or we can lose it at any time
File size
Access Method
Sequentially or ramdomly
Availability
Durability
Frequency</description></item><item><title>VPC (cont)</title><link>/everyday/vpc-cont/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/everyday/vpc-cont/</guid><description>DNS Resolution Domain Name System is a standard by which names used on the internet are resolved to their corresponding IP addresses.
enableDNSSupport (= DNS Resolution setting)
![](https://miro.medium.com/max/1096/1*2OUyyasHqUQUd8HDtsNiCw.png =548x163)
Decides if DNS resolution from Route 53 Resolver server is supported for the VPC
True (default): it queries the Amazon Provider DNS Server at 169.254.169.253 or the reserved IP address at the base of VPC IPv4 network range plus two (xx.xx.xx.2) enableDNSHostname (= DNS Hostname setting)</description></item><item><title>VPC</title><link>/everyday/vpc_note/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 11:15:41 +0700</pubDate><guid>/everyday/vpc_note/</guid><description>Overall VPC contains one or more subnets
A subnet exist in only one availability zone A instance exist in only one subnet =&amp;gt; Create instances in different availability zones
a VPC is only exist in 1 AWS region
3 ways to access resources in VPC
Directly over the internet Over a virtual private network Over a direct connect link If you want to connect from another VPC or on-premise, you can use Transit Gateway</description></item></channel></rss>